

#### OBJECTIVE

Certified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of frontend and backend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering expertise in related fields.

### SKILLS

- Front-End Programming: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, Sass, React, Redux, jQuery,
- Back-end and Database Skills: Ruby, Rails, MySQL,Node.js
- Teamwork and Collaboration:
   Remote pair programming,
   Teamwork, Mentoring, Video
   collaborator
- Software Development Tools: JIRA, Confluence, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Canva
- User Support
- Website Maintenance
- Web and Application Servers

## LANGUAGES

- English | Advanced
- Nyanja | Native
- Zulu | Intermediate

# CONTACT INFORMATION

- richiessikaonga@gmail.com
- 102 high breed Rd, Lusaka Zambia 1 0101
- \_ +27764929880
- Zambian
- @ https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard -sikaonga/

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

# RICHARD SIKAONGA

#### EXPERIENCE

#### MENTOR

AUG 2023 - DEC 2023

MICROVERSE. REMOTE.

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program
- Offered individualized support and advice to mentees on academic and personal challenges.

#### CUSTOMER SERVICE

SEP 2016 - AUG 2022

LONGRICH(INTERNATIONAL). LUSAKA ZAMBIA.

- Provided exceptional assistance to clients, ensuring prompt and effective resolution of inquiries
- Utilized strong communication skills to navigate complex issues with patience and professionalism, fostering positive relationships with customers
- Supported customer needs by inquiring about service and quickly resolving issues.
- Delivered exceptional customer service to each person, skillfully managing stages of buying processes and after-sales support.
- Coordinated with dispatch and service teams to obtain customer support for advanced delivery issues.

#### EDUCATION

# REMOTE FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM, FULL TIME

SEP 2022 - FEB 2024

MICROVERSE. REMOTE.

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# PROJECTS

HAPPY DJ's MUSIC APP This app is designed to help music festival enthusiasts easily find gigs and upcoming events for their favorite DJs. Users can browse through a variety of events, and view artist lineups, this app provides a seamless and enjoyable experience for users to discover and attend music festivals hassle-free.

Built with: (JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3)

SUPER MARIO INFO Dive into the world of Super Mario characters with this fun and informative app. Users can explore detailed information about their favorite characters, including their backstories, abilities, and trivia. this app offers fans a chance to deepen their knowledge and appreciation of the beloved Super Mario universe.

Built with: (JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, and utilizing an API)

BUDGET WISELY Take control of your finances with the Budget Wisely app. This platform helps users manage their expenses, track their spending habits, and make informed financial decisions. this app provides a user-friendly interface for individuals to effectively manage their budgets and make their money work for them..

Built with: (Ruby, Rails, MySQL, CSS3, Bootstrap)

WINE APP Explore the world of wines with this comprehensive app designed to help users find the best wines available. From reds to whites, users can discover a wide range of wines, read reviews, and even purchase bottles directly through the app. This app offers wine enthusiasts a convenient way to explore and enjoy fine wines from around the globe.

 $\label{eq:built-with-postgreSQL} \textbf{Built with: (Javascript, React, Redux, HTML5, Node.js, PostgreSQL, CSS3, Bootstrap)}$ 

# CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

- MICROVERSE: Full Stack Web Development Program 2024
- LONGRICH: Customer Support Certification 2016
- **ZAMBIA:** National Senior Certificate, 2010

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- From Warehouse to Codebase: A Journey into Software Engineering.(2023)
- https://medium.com/richiessikaonga/from-warehouse-to-codebase-a-journey-into-software-engineering-4effb87190f6